Shall I show you?
見せてあげようか
Shall I show you...
what's under this eyepatch?
この眼帯の 下
Open the eyelid that conceals the night
夜を覆う　瞼開け
And fear not the evil shadows
もがき影を恐れ怖がれ
I am as a doll
仄暗き棺から
Born from a dusky coffin
産み落とされた人形のように
With a growing body frozen red
体は赤く凍え
And a heart soothed by darkness
心は闇に　あやされ育つ
Can you see me?
君に僕が見えるかい
My nails steeped in fresh blood
繋ぐ手の冷たさに
Sink into the chill of our joined hands
鮮血の爪立てる
Now, let me see you frown
眉寄せてご覧よ
壊し合おう先に続く謎に満ちる結末を
Let us destroy one another
And face the ending full of mystery that lies ahead
Before we rot away in emptiness
羽も足も　もがれたまま
With our wings and legs ripped away
虚空の中　朽ち果てるように
There is another me
もう一人僕が居て
Who loves someone so much it hurts
誰かを痛いほど愛しているんだ
I wonder, which one is the illusion?
さあ　どっちが幻だろうね
An artificial eye?
義眼
My left eye is a doll's.
私の左目は「人形の目」なの
It can see things that should remain unseen,
見えなくていい物が見えたりするから
so I usually keep it covered.
普段は隠してる
Do you feel ill?
気分が悪い
This might not be a good place for you,
since you're not used to it.
慣れてないと この場所は良くないかもね
Not a good place?
良くない
The dolls...
人形たちが
Dolls are hollow, you see.
人形はね 虚ろなの
Completely hollow, in body and soul.
身体（からだ）も心も とても虚ろ
That void connects them with death.
それは死にも通じる虚ろ
But hollow things seek to fill their emptiness.
虚ろなものたちはそれを何かで埋めようとしたがる
Don't you feel as though this place is
drawing something out of you?
ここにいると 吸い取られていくみたいな感じがしない
自分の内側から
Yeah...
We should go.
行きましょう
It's more comfortable upstairs.
上のほうがここよりマシだから
Do you live around here?
家 この近くなの
Yes.
そう
That thing about "Yomi at Twilight"...
「夜見のたそがれの」っていうのが
Is that the name of this shop?
このお店の名前
Feel free to drop in.
- Studio M
What is Studio M?
「工房m」っていうのは
Kirika's studio.
霧果の工房
It's on the second floor.
ここの二階
Kirika?
霧果
The person who makes these dolls.
上の工房で人形を創ってる人
Kirika
地下の人形も
The ones in the basement, too?
Yes, I think they're all Kirika's.
たぶん 全部 霧果の作品
Why does that doll...
あの人形は何で
look so much like you?
何であんなに君に似ているわけ
さあ
Who knows?
When I first met you,
weren't you holding a doll?
始めて会ったとき 君が持ってたのも人形だったの
Yes.
そう
I heard a girl died at the hospital that day.
あの日 病院で亡くなった女の子がいたんだってね
Was it for her?
その子に
I mean, um...
あの ええと
I think her name was Misaki, or Masaki.
亡くなった子 「ミサキ」だか 「マサキ」だか
Something like that.
そんな名前だったって
Do you have any sisters?
見崎さん お姉さんか妹さんはいる
一人娘さんだったみたいで 親御さんが凄く取り乱して大変だったとか
Apparently, she was an only daughter,
so her parents were devastated.
Why are you...
なぜ君は
Why indeed.
なぜ 何だろうね
I have no other customers.
ほかにお客さんはいないし
Do you have something else to ask me?
訊きたいこと ほかにもあるんでしょう
Well, yes.
そりゃ
A few things seem strange to me.
変に感じることがいくつもあって
Like...
その
I warned you not to get close to me.
近寄らないほうがいいって言ったのに
But it may be too late.
でも もう遅いかも
Too late?
遅い
You don't know a thing about it, do you?
何も知らないのね 榊原くん
There's an old story in this town...
昔話があるの
about the Class 3 of twenty-six years ago.
二十六年前の三年三組の話
I'm guessing nobody has told you.
誰からも聞いてないんでしょ
There was a student in that class...
ある生徒がいたの
who excelled in sports and her studies.
勉強も運動も出来て
She was kind to everyone.
誰にでも優しくって
She was loved by teachers
and students alike.
先生にも 生徒にもとっても好かれてた
But shortly after starting 9th grade, she died.
ところがね 三年に上がってすぐ
その子が死んでしまったの
How?
どうして
The story I heard said she was in
a plane crash with her family.
家族で乗った飛行機が墜落してって話だけど
But there are several other theories.
ほかにも色んな説がある
Some say it was a car accident.
自動車の事故だったとか
Others claim she died in a house fire.
家が火事になったとか
Regardless, everyone in the class
was terribly shocked.
それでね クラスの皆は物凄いショックを受けたわけ
They were overcome with grief.
皆 とてもとても悲しんだんだけど
But then, suddenly, someone said,
そんな中でふと 誰かが言いだしたの
"She isn't dead."
あいつは死んでなんかいないって
He pointed at her desk and said,
その子が使ってた机を指差して
"Look, she's right there."
ほら あいつはそこにいる
"See? She's alive and well."
生きて ちゃんとそこにいるだろうって
Then, other students started
saying the same thing.
そしたらね 同じように言い始める子が出始めたの
"It's true, she's not dead."
本当だ あいつは死んじゃいないって
That behavior spread through the rest
of the class, like a chain reaction.
それが連鎖反応みたいにクラス全体に広がっていて
They didn't want to believe the truth.
誰も信じたくなかった
They didn't want to accept the cruel reality.
受け入れたくなかったのね
残酷な現実を
I'm sure you can relate.
気持ちは分からないでもないでしょう
Everyone in the class continued with that act,
結局 クラスの全員がその後も
insisting that the girl was still alive.
その子は生きているっていうフリをし続けたの
Even the homeroom teacher
took their side, declaring,
担任の先生も協力してね
"It's true, she's alive."
確かに あいつは生きている
"So, all of you should continue
to work hard as a team,"
だから これからも皆一緒に頑張って
"until the day you all graduate together."
皆一緒に卒業の日を迎えようって
The principal even arranged to have her seat
卒業式には校長先生の計らいで
included in the graduation ceremony.
その子のために席が用意されたりもして
Is this a true story?
ね それ 実話
Then, after graduation,
それでね 卒業式の後教室で記念写真を撮ったの
everyone gathered in the classroom
for the class photo.
The whole class, including the teacher.
クラス全員と先生とで
But when they looked at the photo,
they noticed something.
ところが 出来上がった写真を見て皆は気づいたの
There in the photo, off to the side,
写真の隅っこに
they could see the girl
who should have been gone.
いるはずのない その子の姿が写っていたの
Her face was deathly pale,
死人みたいな青白い顔で
but she smiled like all the others.
みんなと同じように笑って
That girl...
その子 その死んだ生徒ね
The student who died...
was named Misaki.
「ミサキ」って言う名前だったの
There's more to this story.
この話にはね
まだ続きがあるの
Oh, sorry.
ごめん
I'm sorry, Grandma.
ごめんなさい お婆ちゃん
Yeah, I'm okay.
うん 大丈夫
I just got a little sidetracked.
ちょっと寄り道しちゃって
I'm heading home now.
もう帰るから
I hate those devices.
嫌な機械
You can be found and caught, anywhere.
どこにいても繋がって捕まっちゃうのね
It's closing time.
閉店の時間だよ
Please go on home now.
今日はもうお帰りなさい
1998 Midterm Exam Schedule
Grade 9 Exam Dates
Math
Science
Social Studies
Japanese
Once exams are over,
we start career counseling.
試験が終わったら進路指導かあ
Having to discuss that formally with
a teacher is so depressing.
改まって先生とそんな話をするっつうのも 激しくユウウツだよなあ
These days, high school
acceptance rates are over 95%.
高校進学率はきょうび95％以上だ
So, don't worry.
大丈夫 きみにも行ける高校はある
There's a high school out there
even you can get into.
Is that supposed to encourage me?
励ましてんのか それ
That was my intent.
そのつもりだけど
Where are you gonna go?
お前はどこ行くんだよ
West High.
西高
Are your grades that high?
お前そんな成績良かったっけ
I'm working on them.
頑張ってるところさ
Yeah...
Well, good luck with that.
まっ 頑張れよ
At any rate, you're stuck with
me until graduation.
まっ どの道お前との腐れ縁も卒業までよ
達者で暮らせ
Keep your strength up!
You're stuck?
腐れ縁
We've been together since 2nd grade.
小学校の二年くらいからかな
We're even neighbors.
家も近所だよ
When we were kids,
we did all kinds of stupid stuff together.
がきの頃はつるんでバカばっかやってたのに
But now he's turned into this
pseudo-honors student
それがこんなアドリブの効かない優等生もどきになっちまってよ
who can't keep up with my improv.
To me, it just looks like you haven't changed.
僕からすれば
君が変わってないだけに見えるんだけどね
I've changed a lot!
俺だっていっぱい変わってんだよ
What do you know about me?
俺の何を知ってるって
I know things about you that
even you don't know.
僕は君が知らない君のことを知っているよ
Like what?
何知ってんだよ
That's how we're stuck with each other.
それぐらい 腐れ縁ってこと
Makes sense.
成る程
So, what are you gonna do
about high school?
で サカキはどうすんだ 高校
Go back to Tokyo?
東京に戻るのか
Yeah.
My dad will be back in Japan by next spring.
来年の春には 父さんが帰国するし
You'll go to a private school there?
あっちの私立に
Probably.
たぶんね
That's one way, I guess.
その手があったか
What do you mean?
何だよ その手って
Maybe I'll go to a private school in Tokyo, too.
私も東京の私立に行こうかな
What school are you going to, Kouichi?
恒一くんは何って学校行くの
え K高だけど
K High.
K High, huh?
K高か
Akazawa, you're going to Tokyo?
赤沢さん 東京へ行くの
If I do, I suppose I'll live on my own.
東京なら 一人暮らしかな
Weren't you going to that Sacred Heart
something-or-other girls' school?
せいしん何とかって女子高へ行くんじゃなかったのかよ
I never said I wanted to go there!
行きたいなんて一言も言った覚えないんだけど
Another one who's trying too hard for nothing.
お前も無駄に苦労してんな
Sakakibara?
榊原くん
Didn't you bring an umbrella?
傘 持ってきてないんですか
No, I didn't think I'd need one.
大丈夫かなと思ったんだけどね
Um...
あの
それじゃ 一緒に帰りませんか
Would you like to walk home with me, then?
My house is just past yours.
私の家は榊原くんの家の更に向こうだから
But...
でも さすがにそれは悪いし
I couldn't ask you to do that.
It's no big deal.
遠慮しない 遠慮しない
Come on, let's go.
さあ 行きましょう
そういえば さあ
By the way,
what do you do for class trips here?
修学旅行って どうなってるの
We went to Tokyo, last year.
去年行きましたよ 東京に
We went to a big amusement park,
大きな遊園地にも行ったし 東京タワーも登ったし
and to the top of Tokyo Tower.
It was so much fun.
楽しかったですよ
You went to Tokyo, huh?
ああ 東京行ったんだ
I love Tokyo, there are so
many fun things to do.
東京 楽しいことがいっぱいでいいですよね
私も東京で勉強したいな
I wish I could go to school there.
Why don't you?
すれば
My family can't afford it.
うちは 無理なんで
Wait, aren't class trips
usually a 9th grade thing?
ってか 修学旅行って 三年で行くものじゃないの
Not here, we go during the 8th grade fall term.
夜見北は二年の秋で決まってるみたいですよ
Although, it used to be in the
9th grade spring term.
昔は三年の春に行ってたみたいですけど
Used to?
昔は
Um, yeah...
I don't know when it changed.
何時頃かは知らないんです
I don't dislike rain.
雨は嫌いじゃないから
Hey, Sakuragi?
あのさ 桜井さん
What is Misaki like?
見崎さんってさ どういう子なの
ダメなんです
Don't...
Don't what?
ダメって
Don't ever speak that name in Class 3!
三組では言ってはダメなんです
What?
ダメって
But why-
Man, the rain's gotten worse.
どうし
ああ 何か雨酷くなってんな
Man, the rain's gotten worse.
Hey, do you know the story about
the Class 3 of twenty-six years ago?
あのさ 二十六年前の三年三組の話って 知ってる
You actually believe stories like that?
お前 その手の話 信じる口だったのか
Yeah...
How...
どうして
How do you know?
どうしてそれを
I just heard a rumor.
何となく 噂で
How much did you hear?
どこまで聞いた
A popular student suddenly died,
人気ものが急に死んじゃって
and then she showed up in the
class' graduation photo.
それから 卒業式の写真にその死んだ子が写ってたって
That's about it.
そのぐらい
Only the first year...
最初の年だけですか
Why do you all look so serious?
どうしたの 三人で深刻な顔をして
Sakakibara knows about the first year.
榊原くんが その 始まりの年のことを
Good morning, Rei!
レーちゃん おはよう レーちゃん
Rei!
Yeah, yeah, morning.
はい はい おはよう
Ah, that's a delicate issue.
そう 難しい問題
Let's try to keep it as quiet
as possible, for now.
なるべくそっとして
やっぱり今は ね
Just keep an eye on things.
とにかく様子を
ただいま
I'm home!
Welcome back.
おかえりなさい
Hey, don't you have exams next week?
あれ 来週試験じゃなかったっけ
Figure they'll be a breeze?
余裕で楽勝って感じ
Not at all.
そんなことないですよ
I'm doing all the studying I need to.
これでもちゃんと 必要なだけの勉強はしてます
Okay then, sorry I asked.
それは失礼いたしました
Man, I'm beat!
今日はくたびれた
Um, Reiko?
あの 怜子さん
Do you remember which
9th grade class my mom was in?
お母さんが中学三年の時って 何組だったか覚えてますか
Nope.
さあ
Then, do you know the story about
the Class 3 of twenty-six years ago?
じゃあ 二十六年前の三組の話って
Reiko?
怜子さん
Um...
あの 二十六年前の三組の話なんですが
I was asking about the Class 3
of twenty-six years ago.
That story's been swirling around for years.
昔から伝わってる話だからね
I heard there's a continuation to it.
その話に 続きがあるって聞いたんですけど
You don't know all of it?
そこまでは知らないのね 恒一くん
知ってるんですね 怜子さんは
You know it, don't you?
That type of story tends to get embellished.
色んな尾鰭がつく物だからね そういう話って
I don't think you should take it too seriously.
恒一くんは あんまり気にしないほうがいいんじゃないかな
There's a right time to
find out about everything.
物事には 知るタイミングっていうのはあるから
Ritsuko was in Class 3.
理津子姉さんは 三組よ
Why, Rei?
どうして レーちゃん どうして
Why?
Hang on.
ちょっと
Entry Prohibited
Yeah?
はい
Are you all right?
大丈夫か お前
Why do you ask?
何だよ いきなり
I called because I thought you were in trouble!
ヤバイと思って駆けてやってんだよ
Akazawa looks like she's
about to blow her top!
赤沢の奴なんか 今にも爆発しそうだし
Why would she...
何で赤沢さんが
Listen, Sakaki.
いいか サカキ
Don't mess with things that don't exist!
いないものの相手をするのはよせ
What are you talking about?
何を言ってるんだ
It's dangerous!
ヤバイんだよ それ
As for that story you asked about yesterday,
それとな 昨日言ってた二十六年前の話
I'll tell you everything next month.
あれ 来月になったら 教えてやるよ
だからさ とにかく今月いっぱいは
So, for the rest of this month, just...
It's about that girl who died at the hospital.
この間のさ 病棟で亡くなった女の子のことなんだけど
Did you find something?
何か分かりました
Her name was Misaki.
名前はミサキだったみたい
Misaki, not Masaki.
マサキじゃなくて ミサキ
The "mi" used in "future,"
and the "saki" meaning "blooming flowers."
未来の「未」に 花が咲くの「咲」
And it turns out her surname was Fujioka.
姓は藤岡っていうそうよ
Misaki Fujioka?
藤岡未咲
その子のことを知りたがってた理由って
Why do you want to know about her?
Um, well...
ええと その
You don't have to tell me now.
今すぐじゃなくていいけど
But someday, okay?
でもいずれ ね
Okay.
はい
By the way, you have exams coming up, right?
と そういや今 試験直前
Yes.
そうですけど
My little brother's studying like crazy, too.
うちの弟も必死で勉強中
You have a brother?
弟さん
Two, actually.
二人いてね
こいつらがもう揃いも揃って筋肉バカでさあ
They're both total muscleheads, though.
They don't care one bit about books!
読書に一切興味なし
I don't think they've ever
read anything except manga.
漫画以外読んだことないんじゃないかな
Isn't that just awful?
問題ありでしょう
May 26 (Tue)
早いね 毎回
You're always done early.
Am I?
そう
昨日も今日も 途中で出てたし
You left before the exam period
ended yesterday, too.
Is everything okay?
大丈夫なの
Yes, I'm fine.
大丈夫なの 私は
藤岡未咲っていう子だったんだね あの日亡くなった人って
So, her name was Misaki Fujioka.
The girl who died.
Misaki...
未咲は
Misaki was my cousin.
未咲は私のいとこよ
We used to be together all the time.
昔はもっと側にいて もっと繋がってた
We were much more closely connected.
Connected?
繋がってた
Hey...
あのさ
About Class 3 from twenty-six years ago...
二十六年前の三組の
What's the rest of the story?
あの話の続きって何
Nobody will tell you?
誰も教えてくれない
No.
I suppose that's understandable.
ま しょうがないか
There's something I've wanted to ask.
前から聞きたかったんだけど
Something I've been wondering
since I transferred here.
転校してきてから ずっと気になってるんだけど
Why does everyone in our class,
どうしてなのかな
クラスの連中 それから先生も どうして君を
even our teachers, act like you...
Because I don't exist.
いないものだから
Listen, Sakaki.
いいか サカキ
Don't mess with things that don't exist!
いないものの相手をするのはよせ
そんな
That's...
It's dangerous!
ヤバイんだよ それ
But...
でも
None of them can see me.
皆には私のこと 見えてないの
What if you're...
見えてるのは榊原くん あなただけ
the only one...
who can see me?
だとしたら
いや
No...
It can't be...
まさか
That's...
そんな
What's wrong with her?
どうしたんだろう
色褪せてく フィルムのように
Like film that loses its color with time
確かな今も いずれ霞んで
The now that we know will one day fade
何でもなく 笑いあった
That fleeting moment's light
When we shared a laugh over nothing
刹那の時間と光
繋がってゆく 記憶の底に
It now lies, waiting to be found, at the depths
誰かが見つけるためあると信じてる 今でも
Of memories that connect one to the next
This I still believe
"Put flesh"